<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>English on 立場舊聞</title>
    <link>/categories/english/</link>
    <description>Recent content in English on 立場舊聞</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>zh-HK</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 16:10:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/english/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hong Kong activist Gwyneth Ho rejects ‘closed-door hearing’, cancels bail attempt</title>
      <link>/topic/hong-kong-activist-gwyneth-ho-rejects-closed-door-hearing-cancels-bail-attempt/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 16:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/topic/hong-kong-activist-gwyneth-ho-rejects-closed-door-hearing-cancels-bail-attempt/</guid>
      <description>A Hong Kong activist withdrew her application for bail on Wednesday after the court decided against allowing the media to report details of her hearing.
Gwyneth Ho, who is among 47 activists and former lawmakers charged under Hong Kong’s national security law, told the High Court that she would not go ahead with her application unless it lifted the reporting restrictions.
Judge Esther Toh, a designated national security jurist, refused to waive the reporting ban and adjourned the hearing after less than 10 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>‘Rights of defendants and public at stake’ in activist’s bid to free media from court curbs on bail coverage</title>
      <link>/topic/rights-of-defendants-and-public-at-stake-in-activists-bid-to-free-media-from-court-curbs-on-bail-coverage/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 19:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/topic/rights-of-defendants-and-public-at-stake-in-activists-bid-to-free-media-from-court-curbs-on-bail-coverage/</guid>
      <description>Gwyneth Ho Kwai-lam
 An activist detained under Hong Kong’s national security law is planning to apply to the High Court to lift restrictions on the media’s reporting of her bail hearing on Wednesday.
In a message published on Tuesday, Gwyneth Ho argued that laws banning the media from reporting details of bail hearings failed to protect the interests of the accused. The press should be allowed to freely report what happened during those hearings, she said.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jabez Lam, a witness to decades of change in UK’s Chinese community</title>
      <link>/topic/jabez-lam-a-witness-to-decades-of-change-in-uk-s-chinese-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2021 17:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/topic/jabez-lam-a-witness-to-decades-of-change-in-uk-s-chinese-community/</guid>
      <description>Jabez Lam (林懷燿)
 “This old man, ‘zaa ba see’ (揸巴士), let’s beat him up!” On the streets of London’s Chinatown, under a billowing Chinese flag, a woman’s voice pierced through the air. A dozen of people immediately started to push and shoved a man around in a busy crowd.
That took place on 23 November 2019. During that period, Hong Kong protesters’ “Daily Schedules” were chock-full of protest activities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thankfulness with no request, says the BNO HK couple who met British PM</title>
      <link>/topic/thankfulness-with-no-request-says-the-bno-hk-couple-who-met-british-pm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 17:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/topic/thankfulness-with-no-request-says-the-bno-hk-couple-who-met-british-pm/</guid>
      <description>Mr and Mrs Wong
 In March, British Prime Minister Boris Johnson spoke via video conferencing to four Hong Kong families who recently moved to Britain, one of which was the Wong’s couple.
Instead of demanding the British government for measures that would benefit the immigrants as they were told to do so, the couple said they did not ask for much during the meeting. “We did not want to ask for this and that once we got here,” they said.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
